Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hello! Good evening, everybody. We'll give the rest, we have about, like.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 10 people here already, 10 participants. We'll give the rest another 2-3 minutes to join, then we'll start the session for today.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Hello, good evening.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Meet me, Jaya.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so it's 7. Let's go ahead and start.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, welcome back, everyone, to the class. Today, we'll be going to… going through Lesson 3.2.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And I'll be taking you through this lesson today.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Today we'll be, going into a kind of brief introduction into machine learning, and we'll explore some of the different types of machine learning models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And yeah, it'll be an introduction, and then I think next week onwards, you'll go a bit deeper into some of the more, supervised techniques, and, so on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, today is just a quick introduction, then the following week you go into more detailed supervised learning, unsupervised time series.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And after that, that's where things start to get a little bit more interesting, where you'll look into more deep learning-based models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For today, the lesson objectives really is to understand the different types of machine learning models, compare different data types, and today we'll have an introduction into, linear regression, logistic regression, and k-nearest neighbors. Three,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Kind of simple, machine learning-based models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we'll break up the session today into two key decks. The first one will focus more on machine learning, after which, the second deck will go a bit deeper into linear regression, and after which we will move into the code, where we will look at linear regression, logistic regression, and k-nearest neighbors.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, a quick recap, I think you've probably seen these, maybe back in Module 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You've heard of terms like artificial intelligence, so this really is more of a… sort of like an umbrella term for any sort of, computer program that tries to mimic the human brain, where, where your program is able to…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, mimic the human brain and come up with different, sort of, predictions, or even decisions based on input, the inputs that it's given.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Machine learning, then, is a subset of artificial intelligence, where we're making… we're training a model based on certain algorithms, based on input data, so that we can come up with, predictions or outputs.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then we also have data science. So, data science, and machine learning kind of intersect together. Some data science… I mean, a part of data science involves machine learning, a part of machine learning also involves data science. But data science also has other aspects, like big data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: data analytics, where it's really focusing on the data, so you're making sense of your data. And a lot of times for data science, it focuses a lot more on statistics, which German,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Focus on in the previous, 3.1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And within the data science, realm also, we have different sorts of algorithms, and approaches as to how we can train different soft models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, here you can see, we have our data science, AI, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and something else additional here would be our deep learning. So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you will focus a lot more on deep learning in the later few classes. This is where you get to touch a bit on computer vision, natural language processing. NLP is really what has gotten… has gained a lot of popularity in the most recent years, ever since ChatGPT, so you can look forward to that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, a quick recap on the data science lifecycle. So, what you've covered so far, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What happens in the typical kind of, like, data science
Shumin Lai  | NTU: project or data science, yeah, project that you embark on. Typically, at the start, it's always very important to first have your business understanding.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So going into any, going into any project, or AI use case that you're going to be developing, it's always very important, first and foremost, to understand the domain that it's in, because depending on different sort of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And… any sort of domain, actually, would have its own, specialized, I mean, special,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sort of background knowledge that you'll need to understand.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for example, if you are going into healthcare industry versus finance industry, there's that additional… you need to spend some time to understand some background on… within the finance industry or healthcare industry, etc, etc, so that you better be able to understand the data, understand why certain data, certain patterns behave in certain ways.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, at the end of the day, all these data has been collected based on,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: events that have happened in the past. So, with the additional domain knowledge, you can then understand the behavior of the data better.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So business understanding is always very important for any database project. And once you have that business understanding, the next typical part that you will go to will be this data acquisition and understanding.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, this is where you go deep, into the data, understanding the data, and this is really where your Module 1 and Module 2 come in. So if you have built any sort of, data pipeline, how you're going to be gathering this data, how often does your data refresh.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Do you have data coming in every few seconds, every minute, every hour, or does your data refresh on a sort of, like, batch basis? Is it a daily, weekly? Yeah, so these are some kind of… these are some of the things you'll need to set up, within your data pipeline.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And of course, your environment, whether it's on-prem or in a cloud, are these typically…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Are some of the decisions you need to make whenever you first kickstart onto a project.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then for your data, whether it's structured or unstructured. So structured, typically, you're looking at more of your tabular data, all stored within your SQL databases. You can also have unstructured data. This can come in more in the form of text, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: yeah, so how you bring in all your, let's say, now with generative AI, there's a lot of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: increase in demand in analyzing text-based data. So, for all these text documents that you're taking in, how do you actually,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Process these documents such that you can extract out entities or key information, and then store it in a more structured format so that you can use downstream.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, of course, for any data, you always have your data visualization, sorry, data validation and cleanup first, so cleaning, removing any sort of wrong data. So, typically for data, you want to, ensure that
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For data, there's typically the four Vs, the velocity, veracity.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: any variety in the volume of your data. So, understanding all that, Ending.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: understanding all that for your data. And finally, we have visualization. So to be able to visualize, in any sort of dashboards.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's also a key capability for your data acquisition and understanding part.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, on the other side, so something which we'll be focusing on from Module 3 onwards is really where the modeling comes in.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is where, once you have all your data, once you have your clean data, once you've understood your domain, gotten all your clean data, this is when then you can start building, models based on your data. So, typically.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: First we will have feature engineering. So once you have your initial set of data, you can then do feature engineering, which is to create more data, more features from your existing data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And I think you'll come across this in your next few lessons as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This is basically to create additional data for your model to train on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Once you have all your data, you can then start training your models. So, here you need to under… you need to first decide what kind of, model you want, and we'll talk about the different types of models as well shortly.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then, for different kinds of models, you also have things like parameter tuning, whether you need to retrain your model, retrain models, and model management.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And of course, for any model that you've trained, you always want to be able to evaluate it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Evaluate in the sense that, is this model good enough for me to push to production and start using,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: On a regular basis.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is… this section is what we'll be focusing a lot more on, in this third module here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Something else that we also have is deployment. So usually, after you've trained your model, and you're done, I mean, the story kind of doesn't end there. You need to then deploy your model so that your stakeholders, your end users, your customers can then start interacting and using this model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, even after deployment, right, that's not, like, the end of it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you always need to monitor your model, so sometimes there may be things called, like, a data drift or concept drift, where let's say there's a change in your behavior of your customers. Change in the behavior of data, for example, then this is when you may need to think, oh, actually, I may need to retrain my model, because there's been a change in the behavior.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of your data. Sometimes it can also be a change in, concept drift. So this is when there's a change in the relationship between your X and Y that you've trained. So, for example, maybe if you're looking at, COVID, right? Let's say you've already trained a model on
Shumin Lai  | NTU: app airline passengers. And then after that, you have this
Shumin Lai  | NTU: event, COVID happening, right? You expect your entire behavior to change. So, you also, once you've deployed a model, you always need to monitor for this kind of
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Data drift or concept drifts, so that you can then, retrain your model, evaluate again, and then push the correct one, the better one, rather, to production, or…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: To use.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, so typically we start with business understanding, go into data acquisition, understanding, modeling.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Deployment, and then, yeah, so typically, if let's say you're looking at this from a consulting perspective, you're developing this for, a customer, then once you've deployed the model, your customer signs off,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then that's it. But of course, you have to do your KT, your knowledge transfer, and then from a customer perspective, they also need to ensure that they have the right monitoring tools in place.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, Module 1, Module 2, we'll be focused… sorry, Module 1 and 2, we will be looking more at the data acquisition and understanding. Module 3, this is when we'll focus more on the modeling.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So a quick…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: question for discussion. You can see, typically, right, these two different skill sets. You can think of it as Module 1, Module 2 is more for a data engineer.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And in Module 3, typically, this is going to be the skill set that a data scientist,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: requires. So, if let's say, you're starting, you're creating your own startup, tomorrow.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: would you hire a data engineer first, or would you hire a data scientist first? What do you think?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any opinions?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: You're on the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A data engineer?
Phillip Tan: I eat this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I'm sorry.
Phillip Tan: It's a science piece of bus.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A scientist first? Okay, so, yeah, maybe elliptic, why, why a data scientist first?
Phillip Tan: Possibly.
Phillip Tan: You need to know what you… you're trying to,
Phillip Tan: Predict and order, right? Then you talk about getting the data, because otherwise, when you collect a lot of data, it's just noise.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: True, yeah, I mean, if you sort of, like, blindly collect data, you don't know what you're cleaning for,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You could…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I mean, you may end up with a bigger mess than if you actually brought in a data engineer in the first place, set up your data governance, your rules and all that, so that you have a more cleaner, sort of data pipeline.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That is definitely one school of thought. Someone else mentioned data engineer first. What was your… your reasoning for that?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I mean, okay, to be very honest, there's no right or wrong answer here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I see in the chat.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Kim Ming and Tao Yuan mentioned data engineer.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Would you like to… to ex… share, share more why you think so?
Kim Meng Phoa: I'm thinking is that the data engine… as a data engineer, he… because he's just startup, so he may not know
Kim Meng Phoa: what other things need to be… to input? So, basically, the data engineer will help him to set out the basic database first.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: ---
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, yes. I think, yeah, yeah. So all these,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, thank you, Kimming. Yeah, so this is a, these are all valid points. So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I mean, honestly, there's no right or wrong answer. Whether you want to hire a data engineer versus a data scientist really depends on your business needs.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, if, let's say, you want to focus… I mean, typically, if you want to, if you think that you're just going to be… you want to just kickstart your business, and let's say, you'll be collecting… you want to kickstart maybe a sales business, for example, and then you're going to have all your sales, so you want to start collecting all your sales data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then maybe a data engineer is the correct way to go first, so that you can start collecting all your data, ensure that it's clean and all that, and then later on, when you think you're ready to take the next step forward to go towards data science, building models, once you've grown to have enough data, you can then hire a data scientist, or even train up, upskill your data engineer if they're willing to have a data science perspective, so that they can start training.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: On the flip side, if, let's say, your startup's going to be focusing a lot more on very tech-heavy, you want to show that you're looking at, maybe some of the cooler, maybe, models that you're going to be implementing within, depending on how you want to, portray your
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your startup, right? Then maybe you want to start building models that you can… you can market first. That's when maybe you want to cons… and then these models, maybe you're building on more smaller data sets, that don't really require large data pipelines. This is when you can consider, okay, maybe I can start with a data scientist first.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: start building these models, and then slowly scale up. Once I'm scaling up, I can bring in a data engineer to help me with that scaling.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hitesh, I see that your hand is raised.
Hitesh shah: So, I would say,
Hitesh shah: It depends on the problem you're trying to solve, so if…
Hitesh shah: If it's a new type of a problem, or a new thing which has not been tested, then possibly the data scientist comes in first. But if you are trying to solve an existing problem, which is from an old industry, established industry, then possibly maybe the data engineer comes in first time.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, yes, that's a valid point as well.
Hitesh shah: Yeah. Thanks, EJ.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So yeah, yeah, really, there's no right or wrong answer. Really depends on, what are the priorities for your,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For your setup.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And of course, with that in mind, so the good thing is that you'll be learning all these, right? You've gone through Module 1 and 2 already, and now you'll be going through Module 3. So you would have both the perspectives of a data engineer, data science… data scientist.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And after this, you can decide which area you sort of prefer.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then you want to go deeper into it, which one you kind of want to use,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We want to be your focus. And, yeah, go deep from there.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hey, so… Let's move on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: a quick introduction to machine learning. So what's machine learning? Really, it's a subset of, artificial intelligence, and the aim really is to learn and improve from experience without being programmed. So you want, this piece of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: program to be able to learn from patterns in the… in the past, in the history… in your history. So if, let's say, you compare, traditional programming, right, it's like maybe your if-else programming, you know, when you have all your different hard-coded rules.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or you can think of it as a calculator. So, typically, you're going to be putting in your data, and you put in this program, so you already know your if and else rules, if
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, your different if-and-else rules that you can code within your program, and then at the end of the day, you get an output, the answer that you're expecting.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Machine learning, on the other hand, is when you put in your data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your… all your X values, and you put in your output as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And at the end of it, you're getting a program. So you're putting in all your history, historical knowledge. So, for example, if you're trying to predict housing prices, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You'll put in all your, within your data input, you'll put in things like maybe your square feet of the house, distance to MRT, distance to nearest shopping mall.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Et cetera, et cetera. So all these are, like, your features, your inputs that you're going to be putting in. Your output is your housing price.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So you feed all this into a machine learning algorithm. At the end of the day, you're going to get a model, a program, so that in the future, when you have new square feet, distance to MRT, distance to your shopping mall, you can feed this into your program, and then get an output, which will be your new housing price.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? As simple as that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So before, I tell you what are the different types of machine learning, models that we have, maybe if y'all can share what are some of the machine learning models that you know of, or if you've even worked through some of these before,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or, it can even be just something that you see in your day-to-day. Like, hey, I know that this is using machine learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah. Anybody want to, yeah, share? So, it also gives you, like, a… it kind of sets your mind thinking about,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: where do you see machine learning first in your day-to-day life, and also if you've built any machine learning models, or know of any machine learning models. You don't necessarily need to know what it does. I mean, what's the algorithm behind, but just…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: No, heard of it, maybe, even.
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Final direction?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sorry?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: Spam collection.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sperm detection? Yeah, yeah, definitely. Sperm detection.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this is a sort of a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: talk more about this. Spend detection, so, like, your emails, right, your daily emails, something that you check every day.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: sometimes you get… you ask your friend, hey, I thought you sent me an email, or even a company, or you're like, hey, I'm waiting for this email, and then you realize it's in your spam folder. So, spam detection, actually under the hood is also a piece of machine learning
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Model that's helping to classify whether or not your email is spam or ham, non-spam.
Josiah Ho: X prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sorry?
Josiah Ho: X prediction, as you're typing. Yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, exactly, yeah. Okay, so this is more, you'll see this a lot more in NLP, in the later,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: modules, but NLP is my personal favorite, area. But yeah, text prediction is, definitely another, it's probably more of, like, a deep learning, where you want to try and predict your next text.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for text prediction, there are different types of language models. There's even a more statistical-based type of language model, and the more transformer-based kind of language models. So, you'll… don't worry, you'll… you'll learn more about this in the later modules.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh yeah, next prediction, another one, another good one.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anyone else?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I see… Minghai mentioned online shopping platform.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, what on the online shopping platform? Maybe you'd like to share more?
Jagatheeswaran Rajagurunathan: recommendations.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Recommendation? Okay.
Meng Hai Teh: Recommendation, predictive behavior.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Pretty safe behavior.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so recommendation, recommender systems, is another kind of, data science machine learning kind of model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For recommender systems, it's a… it's kind of like a special breed of models on its own. Unfortunately, we won't be touching much on recommender systems, in this course.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In the different modules, but recommender systems definitely is another area where it's very data-driven, very data-heavy, and for recommender systems also, it has its own set of problems if, let's say, because it's very data-heavy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for situations where you have no data for cold start, for example, when it's a new user or new product, there are also special ways to deal with this. But yeah, recommendation, recommended systems.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Another huge area where you need a lot of data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, predictive behavior, I'm guessing this is, in terms of predicting, recommending, maybe,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: could be products or whatever to your users, so I would say it's pretty linked.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, great, so Jermaine said if we have time, he can share more on recommended systems.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think we should have time later at the end. I'll… I'll leave some time for you, Jermaine.
germayne: No, no, no, no, not today, not today. I mean, I mean, this is a big topic.
germayne: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Maybe during the coaching classes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, I'll just go through a few more. So I think Ian mentioned computer vision, RNN, deep learning. So, computer vision, RNN, deep learning, definitely. So, computer vision, you will also see this, in the later class, in the later modules. So, this is when you have all your image base.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: More your image, kind of tasks, whether it's, like, classification tasks.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Object detection, etc. Another huge field of, deep learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, yeah, deep learning. Then RNN, this is a kind of, recurrent neural network, something that you tend to see more in NLP as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Which you will also get to see more, Excellent.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You will get to see more, in the later classes as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then last two, Philip mentioned staff scheduling, timetable setting. So, actually, staff scheduling,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Interestingly enough, so…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: we won't be covering this in this, module, unfortunately, as well, but for staff scheduling, this is more towards your operations research, optimization kind of base… optimization-based, kind of models, which I would say is definitely, very…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Important, and it actually is a huge,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Another huge area, because optimization… optimization itself, you can apply it to many sort of, different areas. Staff scheduling is definitely one. Timetable setting.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can think about, you know, even airlines, right? You know, you have many different sort of airlines, to different… your planes, right, going to different countries. How can you schedule all your different pilots and your,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your estudas, and then, how can you arrange all your different planes in an airport such that it's optimized, so that you don't leave, what's that, your boarding gates, empty for too long, or you don't leave a plane there for too long. So all these, optimization also has a lot of real-world impact.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And another very exciting area.
Josiah Ho: about health apps.
Josiah Ho: From your smartwatches and stuff like that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Definitely, definitely. So your health apps,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we will touch a bit on time series, I think, in one of the next course, next week or so. So, your smartwatch, right, you know, based on your cadence, it can also
Shumin Lai  | NTU: it has a lot of data, right? It has your cadence, I mean, your number of steps, your heart rate, your blood pressure, etc. It has all this data. All these data, as long as there's a lot of data, right, you can firstly, definitely do analytics, and you can also do prediction. So, from your, steps, right, your cadence, your watch can predict
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Rather… classify, rather.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: classify whether you're walking or running, because based on a taller person or a shorter person, you know, the walking speed, whether the shorter person is running and a taller person is walking, based on the specifics, all that. Based on all these data, basically, you can also do,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: classification. So yeah, definitely a whole treasure chest of, data there for, to… to do all sorts of, analytics and predictions. But of course, then there's the PDPA, that's a whole…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: AI, responsible AI, and ethical AI is a whole other, the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Topic. Heavy topic on its own.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Anomaly detection in a process.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anomaly detection? Definitely, yeah. So, anomaly detection…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We'll also be touching… you'll be touching on this in the next few comments, yeah. This is when you are really looking at, and for anomaly detection, this is when, you think about
Shumin Lai  | NTU: if you have a 99% accuracy rate, is that considered good? Because for anomaly detection, typically, you're looking at very rare events, right? Like, maybe happening in the 0.01% kind of events. So, yeah, the anomaly detection is also another huge, exciting area on its own.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so I think, yeah, a lot of you can see that, you, you are aware of, like, all these kind of different, machine learning,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: things that are happening in your day-to-day life, or even… or even some of… or you've even heard of some of the different types of, different areas, like computer vision, RNN, reinforcement learning. These are different types of models that we can also build based on different types of data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, for those of you who have never heard of computer vision, RNN, reinforcement learning, are hearing this for the first time, don't worry. Through the period of this, course, you would be able to decipher and understand better what each of these means, and what are some of the use cases, you can use each of these for.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So today, it may sound a bit foreign and strange, but at the end of Module 3, when you think of computer vision, deep learning, reinforcement learning, you'll be like, hey, I actually know what this is, I know some of the use cases for this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, so, okay, so different types of machine learning. I'll just go through this quickly. We have our supervised learning here, and unsupervised learning, reinforcement learning, and actually.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Machine learning is an area where there is a lot of research, going on, so slowly you would actually realize that there's other types of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: machine learning, or even machine unlearning, kinds of, areas around. But not to confuse you today, we will just focus on these
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 3, or rather, today we'll focus… today we'll learn mainly on supervised learning, and then through the rest of the course, you will learn about, some of the other, types of machine learning as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So I think I have slides for each of these, so I'll go through them. So supervised learning, what's supervised learning? So, as the name suggests, right, supervised, this means that you have a set of input-output pairs.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this means that within your data, you have your X values, and you have your Y values. You have your data, and you know what you want to predict.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For example, you have your, features, so if, let's say, you're doing, spam classification, right, your email's coming in, you want to be able to predict whether it is spam or not spam.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, within your… your… your data, you already know your email content, you have all this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You also have a label to say that this email is spam, this email is not spam. So you have sort of, like, the answer key, the output that you're trying to predict. So, you have this, you can think of it as your questions and your answers. So, you have your input and your output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So it's… it's really as simple as, you give your input and output to your model, and then you'll be able to predict for future data coming in, you'll be able to make future inferences on new data coming in, what is the output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, typically what the training process would be is, first you want to have your labeled data, the labeled data set. Labeled data set in the sense that you have your labels.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then you would fit your algorithm, your… your model on your dataset, and then finally you would want to evaluate it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: compare it with the actual labels and evaluate. So, depending on the kind of model that you are looking at, there are different types of evaluation metrics that we'll also be looking at.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for data science, a lot of the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: models that you'll be building, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I would say it's a little bit of an art, in the sense that, especially when you're looking at more of these machine learning kind of models, when you're looking at prediction and classification, it's really more of a… I say it's more of an art because a lot of times when you have your features, right, it's how creative you can get with your features.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: what kind of interesting features you can actually come up with, and that can actually help improve your model performance. So, for machine learning especially, the more… typically, the more and the better features you give your model, you tend to see your performance of your model do better.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, it's really how creative you can get, and of course, this is when your business understanding of your domain knowledge comes in very handy, because when you understand the domain better.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You'll then be able to think of, new features, or work with the subject matter expert, work with the domain expert, to understand what are some of the different features that can affect,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: an output. So, for example, if I say I want to predict, spam, right? What are some of the,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What are some of the labels, features you can think of?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: as if you want to predict spam, right? Maybe you'd say that first you want to have your email content.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then sometimes… You can say things like, the length, Length of the subject.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can also say, maybe, who is the sender?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can also… you can also add, features, like, is there emojis?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Emojis within the subject, emojis within the,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: content, etc. So it's really, you can see, it's how creative you can get with coming up with different sort of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Features to fit into your model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And this is, of course, where you then bring in a subject matter expert. Maybe you bring in a spam email expert to say, oh, okay, so out of all the different kinds of spam emails, what do you think, are some of the data that I need to bring in? And then from there, they'll tell you things like, oh, maybe, you can have categories of emails, whether it's, sales emails, whether it's,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Et cetera, et cetera. So you get the idea.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A lot of times, it's working very closely with your domain experts to understand the domain well, so that you can then find a way to bring this into your model, so that your model can train, and
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Predict better, for your output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then next, we have, unsupervised learning. So, for unsupervised learning, again, we'll cover more of this in the later lessons, but essentially what unsupervised learning is, right, the key difference between supervised and unsupervised is that
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you don't have explicit instructions on what to look out for. So previously, right, in supervised learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You have your input.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And output, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Versus in unsupervised learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You only have your input.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you don't have the output, basically.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you don't have the… you won't be able to tell your algorithm, okay, I'm looking to predict housing prices. Basically, you have all your data, you have, like, your square feet, you have your number of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Distance from MRT, distance from Parker Center,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: number of bedrooms, number of bathrooms, for example, etc. You have all this data, but you don't have the output that you want to predict.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, unsupervised learning, why do we have to share it? Because, firstly, depending on what kind of problem statement you have, so one common problem statement for unsupervised learning could be, customer profiling.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for example, you have your customer… you have a whole, data of all your different customers.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you don't know what you want to look for, so you can just fit this customer data into a clustering model, for example. And what happens is that this model will then try to group similar customers together.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then from that, you can try to make sense of these clusters.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And who knows, maybe you'll get interesting,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: kind of profiles from your data. Maybe you'll find out that, oh, one group of people,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Tend to like to, maybe…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Maybe, more… are more active at night.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then you'll see that their behavior, is all at night, for example. So, essentially, unsupervised learning, really, what it is, is that, you… you sort of don't have the output that you are looking for, but, you just fit in your data to this model, and it's able to come up with an output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But it's not something explicit that you're telling the algorithm to… to do.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, some of the common algorithms, models that we have here is clustering, and dimensionality reduction. So, typically, dimensionality reduction, you can think of it more as a precursor step to a model training, and, you'll learn more on this in the next few lessons as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? But essentially, unsupervised learning, really, the aim is to identify any patterns within your data, because ultimately, you only have your input data, you don't have your output. Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And also because, sometimes data labeling, right? Data labeling is called, data labeling basically is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh, you may have heard of data annotation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: can be a pretty expensive, process, where you actually hire someone to come in and manually really go through all your data. So maybe if you have
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your housing prices, right? You have all your different information, then you ask this person to go through every single house and ask them, oh, how much did you sell this house for? Collect all that data. It's a very manual, tedious, expensive process as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that's why, sometimes as a fallback, I mean, before you actually collect that data, you can consider looking at maybe unsupervised learning to identify if there's any sort of patterns or structures, within your data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, and dimensionality reduction, you'll see also another common use case for this is, visualization. So sometimes you just want to throw in your data, and visualize it so that you can see whether there's any sort of groups, common groups within your data, and then see how you can, work from there.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So yeah, so this is actual bison. Really, you just want to explore the data for patterns. There's no correct answers.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And finally, the last type of machine learning that we'll be touching on, is reinforcement learning. So, reinforcement learning is another special kind of machine learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Unlike supervised and unsupervised learning, we want to train a model that is able to, so-called learn by itself.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, typically, the setup for reinforcement learning is that you're going to have an agent.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Basically, this is the… the model that's going to make decisions, and you will give it an enclosed environment… an environment. So you put this agent within an environment, and you will ask it to do tasks.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And from there, based on whether it does the task correctly or wrongly, you'll then give it a reward or a penalty. So, this agent, at the end of the day, is trying to,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Learn, through trial and error, to try… through trying different approaches, different ways, learn what is the best
Shumin Lai  | NTU: way, and ultimately, this agent is tuned such that, it wants to get more reward and, reduce the penalty. So every time you reward the agent when it does something correctly, it will then learn that, okay, this is, I'm doing something correctly, and then I want to do more of, do more of that, basically.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, an example of reinforcement learning, right,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you know, like, your different… I'm sure all of you have used ChatGPT, or Claude, or Gemini, some sort of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Large language model, or at least a chat interface, before it?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you know that probably, oh, if you try to ask the, the model, like,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: how do I make a bomb? Or what is a Molotov cocktail? Or basically, you ask it something that is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: what's the correct word? You ask it something malicious in nature.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The model, the LLM, has already been…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: tuned, so that it will answer you the, oh, I'm sorry, I'm unable to give you a response on that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, all this, we call this, LLM alignment.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But essentially, what's going on behind the scenes is, we're using something called reinforcement learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: RLearning with…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you know, if you've used ChatGPT, Cloud, Gemini, any of these, large language models before, you know, you have a thumbs up, thumbs down, right? You can give a thumbs up, thumbs down to each of the, responses.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, same thing, right? So the researchers have, have done, intensive reinforcement learning, with Humanit Loop on these LLMs. So it's whenever they ask the LLM, the large language model, for very malicious kind of queries, like, how do I make a bomb, how can I carjack,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Tell me how to carjack. What… how can I hack into…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: website, or whatever, when you ask all these kind of malicious prompts, right, what happens is the researchers, I mean, or the users would then give a thumbs down, so this would then indicate that these are negative responses. So it would then… we can use this data to tune
Shumin Lai  | NTU: these LLMs such that it learns to not give these kind of response. So, it's,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for safety purposes, of course, but yeah, it's to train the model, the LLM, such that it doesn't give,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Malicious, harmful, unsafe responses.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this is also an example of reinforcement learning, but more with human in the loop.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for our…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Plus, today, we'll be focusing off the three different types, right? Unsupervised, supervised, reinforcement learning. Today, we'll be focusing, a lot more on, supervised learning.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, now we'll come to, the important part, which is the data, different types of data. So, when we're looking at data, there are many different kinds of data, variables. First, we have our numerical data. It's…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I guess this is pretty basic, but just bear with me. So we have our discrete and continuous data. Discrete, really, this just means that it's something that is finite, and it's countable. So you can say it's, like, basically
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 1, 2, 3, there are, like… if, let's say, you think of it as the number of employees in a company, there are 328 employees, there's 1,000 employees, it's a, integer.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So these are discrete in nature.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Versus when you are looking at something that, is infinite in nature, In fact…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Within a range of values. So, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the height of a person. So, someone can be 1.82, for example, or 1.65, or 1.93. So, it's, continuous in nature. So, I think these are really more like floats.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so typically when you have your data coming in, if let's say you're looking at, housing prices, right, and you're trying to predict, housing prices, and then you have
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So knowing whether it's discrete or continuous helps you with your data checks. If, let's say, you have a house that has
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 12.5 room.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then potentially, you would say, like, hey, this doesn't make sense, right? 4.5. Number of rooms is supposed to be discrete in nature? Why do I have a 4.5 room? So then you maybe want to go and check, is that a data entry error, or was it supposed to be 4 rooms, or was it supposed to be 5 rooms, for example? So, knowing whether your…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Variables that are supposed to be discrete or continuous, can help you with your, data governance to check your data, ensure that it's, correct.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Same thing if, let's say… I mean, yeah, typically it's more of, when it's supposed to be discrete, and then you see that it's continuous in nature.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so this is for numbers, more quantitative values. On the other hand, we have other kinds of data, which is categorical in nature. These are more qualitative. So, these are your different sets of categories, and for categories, typically, we have 3 different types.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: First is going to be your nominal. Nominal just means that there is no intrinsic ordering, so there's no sort of hierarchy within your categories.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Let's say if you're looking at color, red, blue, green, there's no sort of… red… you can't say red is more than blue, or blue is more than green, or red is three times or blue, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, these are really more nominal in nature. So, there is no sort of… Hierarchy within these categories.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then you have your ordinal kinds of data. So, for ordinal, this just means that, there are… there is a hierarchy, there is an intrinsic order, within this data. So, for example, education level, you have primary, so you have things like,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Primary, secondary, tertiary, JC.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: unique.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you can say that secondary school is higher… is a higher level than primary school. JC is a higher level than secondary school, for example. Or if, let's say, you're looking at, t-shirt sizes, right? Small, medium…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: lunch.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? All these are more ordinal… ordinal in nature. It can also be the number of star ratings, whether 1 star, 2 star, 3 star, 4 star, 5 star.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: all these, y'all can see, all these are more ordinal in nature, so there is an order, within the categories. You can say that a 4-star rating is less than a 5-star rating, so you can do a sort of comparison amongst the different, categories.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And finally, we also have binary.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, binary is just a special type of categorical data that only has two levels. So, for example, gender.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And biologically, gender only has male and female.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of course, now there may be other kinds of, gender, but, for biological
Shumin Lai  | NTU: gender, we only see, male and female, so it's just two… I mean, there's just two, unique values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: light switch can either just be on or off, there's no sort of in-between. So, yeah, for binary, typically you're just looking at any sort of categorical data with two
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Categories.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, let's go through a quick glossary. So these are just terms, that we'll be using.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: whenever we talk about, data. And so, later on, you'll hear me, when we talk about… when we're going to train office model later on, right, you'll hear me say some of these terms. So, what do each of these mean? When we talk about a variable, a variable is basically anything within a data. So if, let's say, you know, you have your whole Excel of data, right? A variable just means…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anything within that training data set. So let's say you're trying to predict housing prices, right? Housing price,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: number of bedrooms, number of bathrooms, distance to MRT, all these are your variables. Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then features, is part… a feature is also a variable, but a feature is typically known as the X values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the data that you're going to be using to predict. So, things… so, so in the housing price prediction, right, your square feet, your distance to MRT, all these are called features. Basically, all your X values that you'll be using to train, your model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then the label is basically known as the Y value. The Y here is basically the output, the target.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or the dependent variable. So these are basically what we want to predict. You can think of it as the answer key for this algorithm. I mean, ultimately what this algorithm is going to be predicting.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Init algorithm here just means, what is the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I mean, what is the program's rules, that this machine learning model will be, trained on?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And of course, model, this is just your machine learning model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Andy, any questions so far?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Uncle?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so we'll carry on. So for today, later on in the code, you will see that we'll talk about two different types of supervised learning models. We have our regression and our classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, these are all supervised learning. So, supervised learning, right, if you recall, just means we have an input and an output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so for regression, when we're looking at regression-based models, this is when we're trying to predict any sort of numerical output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So for example, your housing prices, your temperatures, any sort of, continuous value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: this is when we typically use regression, okay? So it's going to be more of a…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Quantity that can take any… a value of any range, and it's going to be more continuous in nature.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: On the other hand, we have classification. So, classification means you are going to predict a categorical output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for categorical outputs, this just means things like spam and not spam, or if, let's say, in an image you want to predict whether you have a cat or a dog.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So these are categorical labels, and this predicts a class or a category.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this one, for classification, it's always going to be,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: discrete, and it's going to be finect. So it's based on your training data. So if my training data only has chat and dog.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For my output for any image, it will only have cat or dot.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It will not have.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: hamster, suddenly, for example, okay? So, when you train a classification model on your data, it will only be able to
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Do… do future predictions, within your finite list.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That it was trained on for classical machine learning models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, there are different algorithms that we can use, and we will see some of them today. So, for regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We have different algorithms, like linear regression, so we'll touch on linear regression later. There's also different… other sorts of algorithms that you can use, like decision tree, random forest, SVM. You can even use deep learning, models to do, regression, modeling.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? But for today, we'll introduce linear regression later.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then for classification, we also have other models, like logistic regression, which we will be introducing later, but I think something that, you'll notice, right, is that here we have things like
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Decision trees, random forests… SBM, right? So you see that actually,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Some of these models, can be used to do both regression and classification, of course, with some tweaks. And I think you'll see a bit of this in the next few lessons as well. Thank you? But for today, we will focus on our logistic regression and linear regression models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: On.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Here,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: what will my housing price be in my town next year? So this, you see, what's the difference, really, between regression and classification?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Here, you are predicting a housing price, so this value that you're predicting is continuous in nature. What's my housing price going to be next year? Or what is the housing price going to be in… for example, if you trained
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For different HDBs, right? Maybe, you want to say, oh, what's the housing price going to be for Cho Chukan, for example?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for a new unit that's coming, a new BTO that's coming up. What's the housing prices going to be like for this new BTO, for example? And you've trained…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: this model based on all the different HDPs within Troutucan. So then for a new BTO project coming in, you want to predict what will the housing prices then be for, this new BTO project.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, that is a regression… a regression-based model, when you're trying to predict a value that's continuous in nature. You can also predict, maybe what are the temperature prices going to be.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh, sorry, what are the temperature… what's the temperature going to be, next week, for example? So, whenever… so… so maybe that's more of a time series, model, but basically when you're predicting something that is more, continuous in nature, this is when you're looking at a regression model.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I, I thought, I, I thought…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh, okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, thanks a lot. Okay, so yeah, so anything that's more continuous in nature, it's your regression models. And then for classification, on the other hand, is when you are, predicting, labels, categories. So.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For… will the houses be affordable in my town next year, for example? Would you be predicting affordable or expensive?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right, it's just a label. I'm just predicting. Okay, so based on this, based on this, this…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for this new Trajukang BTO project, right, will the prices be affordable or expensive? I'm not going to predict, oh, this unit is going to cost.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 200K, for example. I'm not going to predict the exact price. I just want to predict affordable or expensive. This is when you're looking at classification, more discrete,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Discrete labels.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, everyone clear on the difference between regression and classification?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anyone has any questions?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or is this too easy for some of y'all?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Everyone okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, then we'll move on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, hmm… Okay… I think this is actually the last slide for this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, it's about 7.57 now, so maybe let's take a quick 10-minute break.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then we'll come back, and then when we come back, we're going to be zooming in onto linear regression. So we'll zoom into our first, machine learning model, okay? So we'll come back at about,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It will eat.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, welcome back, everyone.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think I see some of… most of your…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think I see most of your, bag already.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So let's go ahead and carry on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So just a quick heads up, after this…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: deck. We will be going into the notebook, so for those of you who would like to follow along with the coding, you can, start opening your notebooks,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: to just get ready. And, just ensure that you have your ML environment all, set up already, your conduct ML environment, so that you'll be able to follow along later.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, let's carry on where we left off.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For the first one hour, we've been looking into the different types of machine learning, and the different… sorry, the different types of machine learning models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That are available, mainly your supervised, unsupervised, and reinforcement learning. So in this module, in this course, we'll focus more on supervised and unsupervised. And in particular, for supervised learning,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: we learned about, the two different types of supervised… I mean, we learned about two different types of models. We have
Shumin Lai  | NTU: or rather tasks, we have, regression and classification. So these are different types of models, that we can train, and in the area of regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We will be looking at linear regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, linear regression here is a type of machine learning, it has a bit of statistical… it's more statistical in nature, but it's, at the end of the day, still a machine learning model, and the key thing really is, for regression. So, we will be predicting continuous
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Values for this, machine learning model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, and ultimately, through this model, we want to be able to model the relationship between the dependent variable, Y, which is basically your output, and your independent variable, X, which is your features.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so dependent variable, independent variable, this can… this just means your output or your labels, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then your independent variable, this also just…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your X value. Basically, we want to use all our different X values to predict our Y value. So, if you want to predict housing prices, housing prices would be our Y value, square feet, distance to MRT, number of bedrooms, number of bathrooms, these are all our X values, our features, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, at the end of the day, once we have trained a machine learning model, you would get, an equation that looks something like this over here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So why is, the value we want to predict? Let's say this is housing prices.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Beta naught, beta 1, beta 2, these are all coefficients, but the key thing is all these X's. These are all our features. So this can be things like, square feet.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This can be, like, rumble bedrooms.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And this can be a number of bathrooms.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And what we want to use our data to do is to find out what is the best coefficients to fit this model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So coefficients will be all this beta naught, beta 1, beta 2, all the way up to beta N, and this is the error, epsilon.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so linear regression really is, helping us to find out what are these beta values, based on our input data for X and our labels Y.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any questions so far?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so how do we then do this, right? So, linear regression, let's say we want to predict salary.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, it will just be salary. So, for example, here, if you want to predict salary based on years of experience and education level, salary will just be equals to beta naught plus beta 1 times experience plus beta 2 times experience.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So all these beta not values, beta values, so, so this line here is called beta, okay? In case you're wondering why I keep saying beta, these are just, the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the symbols for beta. So beta naught here is the base value, is your coefficient, your intercept value, and then beta 1 is for your coefficient for experience, and your coefficient for education.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you notice, right, what happens if my experience is zero, and my education is zero?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then my final value, salary, will just be beta naught, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, that's why beta not here, the intercept is really your base salary when you have zero experience or education.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, beta naught here is also sometimes called the intersect.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I, so, so, if y'all know about, you know, I think maybe…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Last time in primary school or secondary school, probably learned Y equals MX plus C. I don't know, I hope if this is familiar.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? Then, you learn about… you have a graph, And then you… We are.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Y, and you would have your X.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, let's say we have a graph, y equals MX plus C, Right, if you recall, this… Here?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: MX plus C. C will be your intercept.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And your M is just the gradient.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right, you just take one point, whatever. So the gradient is your M.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So, this is exactly what we're doing in linear regression. We are just fitting our data, into a best fit line. So this is when we have a single, Y equals MX plus C. This is when we have one feature, when we just have
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For example, if we just have… If we just… salary, and Beta 1 experience.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right, you can… there's just M…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: plus C. And then this is just arrow.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Ignore prevative education for now.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so this is exactly this thing that we see here, okay? So linear regression is really just fitting your data into this Y equals to MX plus C.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, so we have beta naught, beta 1, beta 2, your intercept, and your x coefficients.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The error, epsilon here is just your error term to account for, random error, your errors. So basically, it's any, for example, if you have unpredictable factors.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For example, for salary, right? You may have, some people may have better,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Negotiation skills, or maybe for certain,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: certain domains, there's more higher demand or lower demand, so that can also affect your salary, other than your experience and your education, for example, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, what are some of the… I'll just go through some of the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: key assumptions. So whenever we're building a linear regression model, we have some assumptions. So first, we always assume that it is a linear relationship between the variables.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: As you can see, it is a linear, relationship, Y equals MX plus C. This is a sort of linear relationship. So first, the variables have a linear relationship.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, you want to ensure that there's no multicollinearity between the independent variables, so your X, right, should not have any sort of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Correlation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For example, if you are looking,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: At salary, right, and you have experience, education, maybe you have, experience, and maybe you have…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Another feature that is related to experience would be
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Number of passage jobs, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: number of previous jobs.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: As a feature. So a number of previous jobs and experience will have some sort of correlation, right? Generally.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the more experience… I mean, not necessarily… there is some correlation. If you have higher number of jobs, you may expect your experience to be higher. Of course, there could be some rare cases where there's some job purpose. Ignoring that, generally, if you have
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If you're assuming everyone generally has, stable,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Ignoring job purpose. When you have higher number of previous jobs, you expect your experience to go up, because you've been in the job market more.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, these two features, Have some sort of relationship.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So if there are features within your model that have relationship, right, this multicollinearity can cause your model to be very unstable, and your coefficients would then be unstable. So your whole model would be unstable, and, you can also see that, when you train the model across multiple times, different times, you may see your beta values jumping around. Your beta values may vary. Basically, you get very unstable.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you want to ideally just choose one.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In such scenarios, just choose one, just use one or the other, or you can come up with another feature that is a combination of the two.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: like, some sort of index, some sort of value that combines these two features into one feature, okay? So, yeah, something to take note of. No multicolinary. Make sure your variables have no correlation amongst between each other. If not, you just choose one.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So I think, probably in Module 1, I think you would have learned about correlation, right? You can plot a heat map.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of all your different features, right? So from there, typically, if let's say you're going to build a linear regression model, you can first do that heat map, and then identify if any of your features have a high correlation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If any of your independent features have a high correlation, you may then choose to just drop one.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Between the two, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, another assumption is, homoscedasticity. A pretty big word, but what it just means is that your error, your errors, so after…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: once you have fit a curve, right, you would have your errors. We'll talk a bit more about this later as well. Basically, you just want to ensure that there's constant variance, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because if your errors have some sort of pattern, then this could be an indication that your model may not be the best model that you're building. There's some additional pattern that you have not yet accounted for within your model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So your errors, you want it to be more random, in nature, constant variance.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If there's some pattern that you notice in your area, this would be an indication that your model, has not yet accounted for some behavior in your data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That's why you're seeing Arab patterns within your Arab.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And finally, we also want to ensure that the errors from our inference, inferred data have a normal distribution. So this also is to ensure that, the coefficients that we have,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: that we've trained here, beta naught, beta 1, beta2. We want to ensure if your errors are not normally distributed, this will then also mean that your coefficients may be more unstable.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And when you do your statistical test, it may not be, statistically significant.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? So, typically, if you see, maybe if your errors are normally distributed, then you may want to go back to your… your model and see if you want to… if there are… firstly, if there's any outliers within your model, within your data that was trained. Or secondly… secondly, you can also look into, doing some sort of transformation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of your… Your linear regression model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Kids. Actually, right, at this point…
Kar Poh Tay: swimming.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah.
Kar Poh Tay: Hi, Sumi, just a question on, does it matter…
Kar Poh Tay: Or any impact on the number of independent developers?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, that's a very good question.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yes, there is an impact. So, later on, we'll see something called R-square. Generally, right.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you want your… maybe we'll talk about it later, but, there is an impact on… based on the number of, variables, and yeah, we'll talk about this, slightly later.
Kar Poh Tay: True.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But yeah, good question.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, the error, right? Can I, can I just…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: just clarify my, my thinking, so it's like… so… so, Linda, you questioned there's error, but we… we want to make sure that the error is, like, constant.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Am I correct, or…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The variance is constant.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Various is constant.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Correct, because if you see, like, for example, right, if let's say we want to model all the houses in Singapore, we want to build a linear regression, a regression model, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you may then see, oh, for all the, for example, all the HDVs you'll see, for example, if, let's say, this is our thing, right? Then maybe you'll see all your… your points like that. These are all the HDB. Then, then maybe you will see some…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Some points here, very high price.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then your error will be very different, right? Because maybe these are, like, condos or landed properties. So, if your error you see very… if it's not a constant variance, you're seeing patterns within your area. There's one group of errors here, one group of errors…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then it's an indication that maybe within your model, there is some pattern that you have not yet accounted for in this model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so then, in this kind of situation, maybe a better approach would be to cut your data. You just train on one linear regression model for all your HDB, another linear regression model for your condos, etc.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, I understand. Thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, good questions. All very good questions.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, let's go to… this… Nice.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Here, I thought it would be good… there's this link here. So all these links, I've put it at the bottom of this notebook, so if you want to go back later and explore, you can go and look through this as well. But here, it gives you a visualization.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of how your linear regression models can be trained, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, linear regression, really, what we want to do, right, first is, let's say here we are trying to predict housing prices.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, housing prices, we're gonna take beta 1 times square feet plus beta naught.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right, so, here, we're just going to have a very easy model. We're going to start… so typically for any, sorry,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for any, models when you start, right? You always want to first start with a naive model, a baseline model, because how can you prove that your model is better, right? You always want to have a baseline model, a simple model, just to prove that, hey, what you're building actually is correct, is better.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for regression, one very common baseline model is just to use the average.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So let's say tomorrow, right, if let's say I ask you to predict, the housing prices of this new BTO in Trachu Kang, for example, what would you do? One way is you can just get the average price of all the BTOs in Troutucan, and then say, okay, I think the average price is going to be
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 300K, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I don't know what the values are, but let's just say it's going to be $300K. The average price is $300K, for example, okay? So then, you can use this as your baseline model. So anytime someone says, oh, how much is this new video going to cost? And they say, oh, I think it's gonna cost $300K. But you can then… so that is your first simple, naive model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then you'll build this, linear regression model to then show, oh, okay, now I have this model that says the housing price will change based on square feet. So for this new unit that you're looking at in Trachukang, how many… how much square feet are you looking at? So then this person will tell you, oh, maybe
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 1,000 square feet.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then you can then say, okay, I'll put this into my model, and then, what is this new price gonna be? Okay? So, that's why we have a baseline model for us. So the baseline model here, let's say, the housing price is gonna be $300K, the average price. So we then start with this naive model that says, okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: All these orange dots that you see here are the different square feet and housing price. So for all these, for everyone, we just say, okay, the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: new price, which is just going to be $300K, okay? So, once you get that, right, all these red lines that you see here, these are the errors. We also call it residues, so if you hear me say residuals or errors, it's the same thing.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: these are the errors. So, with this naive model, right, it's pretty bad, right? Because you see, for this… this house here, that's a pretty high… it's only, like, going to be maybe 50K, but we predicted 300K. So there's going to be, like, a 200 and…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 50K, error, right? You over-predicted by $250K. Then you have this other unit here that is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: maybe $550K, and again, you only predicted 300K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this error is going to be, like, $250K, right? So, essentially, all these…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: All these red lines that you see, these are all the errors in predictions, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we'll move on. So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Now, with linear regression, what we actually want to do is find this best fit line.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Such that the error is minimized as much as possible.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so what is this best fit line that we can find so that we can, fit all the lines? I'm sorry, fit all the,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: data points, okay? And this is basically our… through this line, we will then know what is our beta naught and beta 1, which is our Y equals mx plus c, essentially. What is our intercept, and what is our coefficients?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, once we have this best fit line, next time, now there's this new Cho Chukang BTO, right? So, you can then say, hey, this place has a square feet of, 725.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So now, with $725, the predicted price is going to be $521.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: About 500.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 21K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If the square feet is only 105, then we can say, oh, based on square feet 105, based on our model, we will then predict this house to cost $52K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so this is, from here, you can see this is already an improvement from our blanket 300K naive model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, any questions so far?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: All good?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Explain again, sorry, can you explain again on the residual error?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sure, sure. So, Rescue Duels basically is,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Residual, right? Okay, so let's say I say everything is 300K, right? The residual here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: is the error. So, I say that everything's strategy, right? So, for this point here, if let's say this one was, like, 50K,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then the residual is going to be 300… 300… minus 50… 25.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this is the residue, the error.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because I over-predicted. Because the house here is supposed to be 50K, right? But I predicted $300K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, so now, right, I want to fit a better model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this new model here, clear this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This new model here, right? Instead of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: predicting 300K just now, right? So just now, initially, my naive model, I predicted
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 300K as a blanket for…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For my first model, I say everything's 300K, right? But then now, with my new linear regression model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I then say that, okay, just now I predicted.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's a different color.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Just now, I predicted 300K, but now, for this one, I only predict maybe… 50.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 2K, for example. So, you can see the residual… is now 52K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Minus 50. So now the residual is just 2,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Basically, your error. Your error in prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Is that clear?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hey, so, yeah, so from, from there, you can then predict any, future prices.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, just when we talked about the error, this is the error that we are talking about,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Error is…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: I mean, it's the earliest slide where you talked about the error. Is this this error that we are talking about?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Correct, this is the area we're talking about, exactly, yes. So that's why, if we were to talk about, for example, this all HDB, right? And then, let's say you have some condos here, right? You expect condos, even though for smaller,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Smaller square feet, the price would be much higher.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then you may… you'll see that your errors, you have some very small errors and some very big errors, so you want your error variance to be the same.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You want your error values to be around the same, because you see, if this is your line, right, and you don't have this best fit line here, your errors are going to be very huge for this game.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: this… this… Behavior of houses.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you can see the error magnitude here is much bigger than the error magnitude here. Yeah, so when you see that there's that, you have, you don't have a constant variance, basically. You have errors… I mean, your distribution of errors is not constant.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: there is some funny pattern going on. This is an indication to you that there could be some model
Shumin Lai  | NTU: some behavior, sorry, some pattern that is not yet accounted for within your model. So then you need to go back and look at your data. Then, in this kind of situation, either add in a feature for your, type of houses, or maybe if you have enough data, just create two regression models for each of the, types.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: E.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then, okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so now you can predict, with this line, right, you can have a more flexible prediction for new housing prices based on square feet value coming in.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, for regression model, or actually for any model, right, we always want to… Calculate,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We always want to reduce…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so for regression model, go back a bit. You want to figure out what is this beta naught and beta 1, right? Because now we know we want to fit a line, but how can we figure out, how can we solve for the intercept and the M and the X, the beta naught and the beta 1?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: what is this beta 0 and beta 1 values? So, to solve it, we can actually… we always want to
Shumin Lai  | NTU: There are two ways to solve, so maybe I'll come… To… CFS?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, we want to learn the coefficients. What is your beta naught and beta 1 value?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for linear regression, there are two different ways you can solve. One is gradient descent. So, gradient descent is a bit complex, and I'll leave this for the later modules, because we'll learn about this more in some of the boosting and begging.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: concepts. So, essentially, we're just making use of something called chain rule, to iteratively solve for the beta naught and beta 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: essentially, it's something like this, so you see, if I… it's… you can think of it as I'm just trying many different… I'm changing the weights very slowly.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you see, yeah? One step, right? This just means I shift… I keep finding, iteratively, I keep moving this best fit line. So now I try it here, then after that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I will try to shift it like that. So I just keep shifting this iteratively. It's a very iterative approach, gradient descent. And from there, we will basically want to minimize our errors as much as possible to find this best fit line.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so one way is true gradient descent. So, okay, if you're lost, just know one way is true gradient descent.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And another way for, linear regression is through ordinary least squares. So, the good thing about linear regression is that you can actually solve a closed-form version, of this through matrix,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: multiplication.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: To put it simply. But essentially what's happening, right, is you can see that if, let's say, I just put a few points, right, through math, you can actually solve what is your beta naught and beta 1 value, based on all your data points. So it's basically just solving this, equation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, right now, don't worry too much about this equation, because later you'll be seeing through the code, right, all this is already abstracted away.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You just need to call a very simple library called scikit-lun. You'll see that shortly. You just need to fit in your data, and you'll be able to immediately solve for your beta naught and beta 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? But, essentially, this is how, you can solve for your beta naught and beta 1, how you can get your beta naught and beta 1 values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anyways, I will be… you'll be able to access this link as well, so if you're interested in going into the math, you can spend some time here. And then if you have any questions, you can feel free to reach out as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is how you can figure out your beta naught and beta 1, but something that, we'll want to talk about now also is, how you can evaluate your model. So, now that I have a linear regression model, right.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And let's say, let's say I train one model, and then, let's say Noelle has another set of data, and he trains another model. How can we know which model is better?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we can actually make use of something. So, for different, tasks, we have different metrics. It's like, you know when you take exams, right, you have a score?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, same thing for models, right? There's a score that you can use to… a metric that you can use to measure how good a model is.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for regression-based models, we will be using something called mean square error.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: it's basically how… it's a value, a metric that you use to evaluate. So, mean square error, essentially what it is, is you are taking, your Y value minus your Y hat value squared. So.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: it's Y minus Y hat, right? This is essentially your error, right? Because if, let's say, my prediction
Shumin Lai  | NTU: let's say for the house, right? I've predicted, 300K, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then the actual.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: is maybe $350K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, my error… will just be 15K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Great.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So if I predict, $300,000… Right. So my error is $50,000. So mean square error is basically,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: as you see this notation, 1 divided by N, summation of all the Y minus Y hat squared. So I'll just take all the errors
Shumin Lai  | NTU: squared. So, 50,000 squared, and then I sum everything up.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then divide by N.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so then from there, you can then compare, for two different regression models, you can compare this mean squared error value. Which model has a lower mean squared error?
Hitesh shah: a number of samples, right? And…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, and it's a normal sample. And it's your test data set.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, let's say your test dataset has 100 samples, we have 100 different units in Chuatukang.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then for each of these hundred units, you get your prediction, and you get the actual. You minus find the error squared, sum everything up, and divide by… basically take the average.
Hitesh shah: So if there is one sample, it will be 50,000 square divided by 1. I mean, just for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, correct. If you have one sample, yeah, essentially, yes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But generally, you want to have a bigger test set, so that it covers more area.
Hitesh shah: So, is there a recommended value for mean square error? I mean, it should be within certain range, or it's…
Hitesh shah: Data slot.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, I think, I think you got the answer. It depends on the domain. So, typically for any sort of domain, for example, if you're looking at housing prices, right, you may expect your area to be in the thousands. Of course, you can scale it down, but if you're looking at, other things, like maybe,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Temperature, or,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: rainfall, right, when, the value is a lot smaller. So, typically for every single domain, right, what you want to do is,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: know what good looks like. So if, let's say, you're predicting housing prices, right, then maybe you want to see for Singapore, within Singapore, is there a sort of data set, and is there some sort of,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Standards in terms of housing price prediction, and then you can identify what is the mean square error for those models generally.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then you can expect that is the general range, then ideally, if you can get to that range, or if you can get even better, yeah, so it varies domain by domain, this, best value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, mean squared error is just one metric.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We also have another metric, actually, and this metric is called our R-squared value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: R-squared value is a goodness of fit. So, mean square error, right, it tells you, it literally gives you a value in terms of error. So, like, it literally tells you the error is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The error in your…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your housing prediction, it's in those units, versus R-squared, right? R-squared is more of a goodness of fit, which is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: How well… This linear regression model you've trained captures the variance within, the data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, R squared is another metric, and this is the formula. Essentially, you are taking 1 minus, your mean squared, your… your squared error sum, divide by your
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Total, total error from, your naive model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this Y bar here is just going to be your average housing price, so Y minus Y bar, and then you take your mean squared error, your predicted error. So essentially, right, you can think of it as you are taking
Shumin Lai  | NTU: these errors.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You see all these areas here?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because this is your Y bar.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Your average price.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: All these errors, these errors divide by… these errors.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, I'll show you again. Essentially, this is your denominator.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Your total sum, of errors.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Based on the Y-bar prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And your numerator is going to be your errors from your predictions.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this basically just measures your best fit, the goodness of fit of your, data points. How well your data points fit into this, best fit curve.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, yeah.
Hitesh shah: It has to be closer to 1, is it?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, exactly. So the closer to one, the better.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So if your value is 0.1,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: yeah, then maybe you need to go and identify what are some new variables you can fit into the model to increase your R-squared. Of course, again, there is no… I mean.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: higher the R-square, the better, but depends on the domain also. In certain domains, your R-square can only get as high as 0.6, and if you're getting a 0.61, that's considered very good. So, again, it's domain by domain.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Some domains, maybe a 0.8 is considered very bad. You're expected to get a 0.9 R-squared value. So, for all these, R-squared value as well, same… similar to your mean squared error, typically you want to try to identify what is the best
Shumin Lai  | NTU: practices within that domain? What are the typical,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What are the big guys doing out there for these models, and what are the metrics that they are seeing?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so these are two ways that you can use to, evaluate your model. Mean square error and your R-squared. So R-squared really is just 1 minus this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any questions so far?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, I just have one question. Regarding the R-squared, the denominator, is y' minus
Chieh Cheng Lai: Why? But without the eye. What does this mean,
Chieh Cheng Lai: The wiper.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Y bar is the average of all your values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Ohio.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, all the rich old domain. Alright, understood.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Since… okay, no other questions. Maybe I'll ask you a question. Do y'all think the R-square can be greater than 1?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Isa nos.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anyone think it can be greater than 1?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Key.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, generally, right, if you just… so, if let's say, you… you ever have a situation where your R squared is a very funny number, right, always just come back to your equation and see what… what is happening. So, essentially, you are just taking all your errors from your predictions, divide by your,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: a rich… So, 1 minus… this value can go very… Bake?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So in a situation where your this model is very bad, is worse than your naive model, you can get a scenario where this value is greater than 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then your 1 minus greater than 1, essentially, will always just be a negative value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, generally, you don't expect to see this value, and also because it's square, you don't expect to see this value to be, greater than 1. But you can have this value to be less than 1, less than 0. You can have this value to be negative, and then that would just be an indication that
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Your model is poorly, very badly fit, and then you need to look into it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So yeah, negative R-squared generally just means your model is doing very badly.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Gee, so I'll go back to the slides.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, so essentially, this is our best fit line that we want to fit.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And something that is good about, linear regression, right, is that, so you can see here, once we have this regression line, right, this, this, equation, you see that salary is beta naught plus beta 1X1. You know that your beta naught, your intercept is 40,000,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This just means that, here we're looking at how salary changes based on years of experience. For 0 years of experience, the average salary is about 40K.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this just indicates that, okay, generally, on average, you can, you can start off with a 40K, salary.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this beta 1 coefficient being 2,000, can someone interpret this number? What does it mean if we say this beta 1 coefficient is 2000?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: How does that, translate to experience and salary.
Teng Lee LIM: Is it for every year of additional experience?
Teng Lee LIM: The salary increased by… By 2,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, exactly, yeah. Thanks, Amy. Yeah, so exactly.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For every year, every unit change, every year increase in your experience, your salary will increase by $2,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so you can see that, your regression model is very,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: explainable, right? It's something that you can easily, interpret.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So if, let's say, you have a data point, and then… and then your user comes in and says, hey, how come this, this person has been predicted to have such a high salary? Then you can actually go back to your data and say that, oh, because you see, the years of experience is, much higher than the rest, so that's why, salary was predicted to be higher.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, so explainability is another component, a concept, that we have within, machine learning as well. So there's a whole area of study, in explainable AI as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And some models, like linear regression, is very easy to explain. It's very explainable. But you will also see some models later on, especially when we look at your more deep learning models. This is where we call these models, like, a black box. So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you kind of… it's very hard to explain what's going on, why the model predicted, image to be a cat, or why it's a dog. So, of course, there's more research being done in the area, and slowly we have more explainable,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: approaches that we can apply on these models. But yeah, always bear in mind, whenever you're building a model, and depending on the domain, so especially if you're looking at maybe more stricter domains, like, for example, you're looking at finance, you're looking at insurance, you're trying to, predict whether or not insurance claim is going to be fraudulent or not, right? You always want to ensure that you bring in an explainable component.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because when your customer comes to you and says, hey, how come my, claim was not, approved?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you want to be able to explain, oh, because of this, this, this, or because of that. So, explainability is also, an important,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Concept to think about whenever you're
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Building your own machine learning models as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Dude, that's not… that's not what we talk about… It's learning the coefficient.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: But I never… so, the name is Beta Zero.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Or beta 1, whatever, right? So, but I never, I, I maybe explained it, but I, I really didn't get it, whatever.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: So, after learning the coefficient, I mean, like, what do we do with it? I mean, like, are we going to say that, oh, this model is wrong, or…
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Are you gonna say that, oh god.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Once you learn this coefficient, right, so let's say now I have this model, salary…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: equals to, 40K… plus 2K times experience, right? Then, let's say someone else has another model, salary.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It goes to 35K… Less.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Cheeky.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: times experience, right? Let's say we have these two models. Then, your next question will be, what is the MSV mean squared error, right? You know, that's how we learned about mean square error, right?
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: and the R-square. So then you can then compare what is the mean square error, And, Spain.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Okay, okay, so you see how good the fit is, lah?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Correct, correct. So then you can see which model is better.
Low Keng Teck, Noel: Thanks.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so we'll move on. So, yeah, so, so, yeah, we talked about mean squared error. Mean squared error here basically helps us to evaluate, how good our model is, how's the performance of the model. Essentially just take every single value, Yi minus, Y hat squared.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anybody knows why we want to do a square?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any guesses?
Zac Ang: Remove negative numbers.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, thank you, Zach. Yeah, so imagine if, let's say, I have, if I have,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A salary that was supposed to be $2,000… $40,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But I predicted.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 30, but I predicted 50,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right, and then my error will be negative 10,000.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, if we square it, we can,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: remove the negative, essentially, right? So that if you don't do this, right, then, when you have negative 10,000, then someone is, above 5-10,000, this may cancel out. So we don't want the errors to cancel out. We want to be able to collect all these errors, so we can square it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Another reason for, using, mean squared error, also because, when we're looking at this concept of ordinary least squares, when we are minimizing the mean squared error, it's,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's a quadratic equation, so it's a more bowl-shaped convex kind of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: equation. So through the closed form, so we'll be able to get a closed form, response. So we'll be able to basically solve this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: To get our beta no and beta-1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: through OLS approach.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: there's also a gradient descent approach that you can use for training a model. You'll learn more about gradient descent in the later classes. But don't worry too much about this. You'll see later in the code, right, you just need to call your linear regression, and…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you will get your Beta 0 and Beta 1, as simple as that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, here you can see that
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You know, just now we were just looking at one, feature, right? Years of experience and salary. But, I think just now a couple also asked a very good question. How many features can you add, right? You can add more and more… you can add a lot of different features, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So let's say, and just now at the start, we also talked about how data science is a bit of an art, in the sense that, you want to try and identify what are all the, important features
Shumin Lai  | NTU: in a domain. For example, if you're…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: predicting salary, right? It's definitely not just years of experience or education level. Maybe even the previous, your past history, what, what,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What… what companies you are in, maybe what domain you're in,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: maybe if you have a referral or not, all these can… are other factors that can also affect your salary, right? So, typically for, any… not just regression, right? Any sort of model, you want to find out,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You're gonna find as much,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: relevant data, as much features as possible, that can help you model this,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: pattern, this behavior that we are trying to model. For example, model salary. You want to try and figure out what are all the unique, features that are available
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But of course, there can be a thing as too much features, because you don't want to… I mean.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: if we just, if we were able to just fit all these features into a model, right, and then train a model, right, then, and the more the features, the better, right? Then you can just throw in all your features, even, like, redundant features, and then just train the model. So, I mean, you can't do that. So, there is, something called…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: bias and variance, which you'll also learn in later lessons, about how you can look at the error. So just now we learned about mean square error, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: there can be a test error and a validation error, and you can compare that to try and identify whether you have too much data or insufficient data. So these errors, right, will give you a signal whether or not you have sufficient data or insufficient data, whether you're overfitting or underfitting a scenario.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And from there, you can then decide whether do I need to get more data, in the sense that,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: maybe now I only have 1,000 rows of data. Do I need to get 10,000 rows of data, or do I actually need to get more features? Do I need to collect more information from the domain to fit into this model?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So there are different, signals, whether it's overfitting, underfitting, that you can use to help you decide what kind of data, how much data you need to add.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, something else also to point out that is your R-squared value, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So R-square value, how it's calculated, essentially, is your sum of square total, right? Your YI minus y bar squared.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This is your…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Y bar is your, average value, and then you take your sum of squared residuals, divide by this value, right? This is what we saw just now for R-squared value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So basically, this is the same plot, your Y bar, your mean value, so divided by your… I mean, sorry, your, residual divided by your Y bar residual.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This is your R-squared. So generally, right, the more… for linear regression, unfortunately.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: when you add in more features, it will also cause your R-square to go up, so this is just something to take note of. If you have…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 10 features versus 100 features, and even if your 100 features are redundant, you'll see that your R-square is also higher.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So sometimes, R-squared doesn't… so that's why here you'll see that, R-squared doesn't guarantee that it is the best model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of course, there's an overfitting risk, and there's also another risk that you are fitting in,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the more data you fit in, generally, you would expect your R-square to go up.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Is, anyone… anyone confused?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Do I need to explain that again?
Hitesh shah: Yeah, very good.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, R-square, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: naturally, your R-square, the higher, the better. Higher R-square indicates better, better fit of a model, but R-square can also increase when you add in redundant features. It's just that the increase you will see is a more minute scale.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you can try training a linear regression model with 10 features, and then you can try training with 20 features. Your R-square will go up, but if your features are irrelevant, your R-square will go up by a smaller,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you're asking me to go from 0.5 to 0.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Bye.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: tree, for example. So the increase will be very small.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Even though you add a large number of redundant features. So, R-squared isn't always the best, metric.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you can always take it with a pinch of salt. That's what I'm saying.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Typically, more often than not, you'll want to look at your error term, because your error is exactly telling you what is the magnitude of the error, that you have.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Within… when you are fitting a model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: R-square really is just more of an indication how well does this model,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: fit on your data, but error tells you how much is it off by. Is it off by $50,000? Is it off by, $30,000, etc. The error tells you the magnitude, how wrong your model can be. R-square just tells you how well it fits, essentially.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so there is a difference between these two metrics. It's good to know the difference, but of course you can use these two metrics to compare across different models to finally decide, which model you want to push to production.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I'll deploy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Teng Lee LIM: Sorry, can I ask something? Jessa, you were saying that…
Teng Lee LIM: if there is overfeeding, right, it's also not good. But I thought, like, the more data you've given, then
Teng Lee LIM: the… I thought that would be… you would get a better result.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: - Okay, so overfitting, I'll just do a quick
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Overfitting, what this means, right, is that it works very well on your training data, but when you deploy it to production, right, you see this model does very badly. Because essentially what it means, right, is that your model memorized,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: this data set. And then when it has new data coming in, right? Because ultimately, when you train a model, you want it to be able to,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Do well for new data coming in.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But if your model only trains well on this training data set, right, then for new data coming in, it does badly. It's not a good model, still. Even though you can think of it as, you know,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If you're doing an exam, right, and you memorize all your notes, and then you learn the notes very well, right, and then you go for the exam, you do very well, but because you memorize these notes, but when you go out, and then you realize the real world, there's other,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: There's other…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: kinds of data out there, and you don't do well there. So, you want to be able to do well in the exam and in the real-world scenario.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: don't worry about this overfitting concept too much, because it will be covered more in depth in the later classes. Yeah, this is more just to introduce that, R-squared doesn't always mean that it's good. Typically, you want to look at R-squared and mean square error as well.
Teng Lee LIM: Thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we'll do a quick summary. For linear regression, we learn about the linear equation, what are some of the assumptions, and your evaluation metrics. So.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Evaluation matrix is very important when you want to compare, new models. How do you decide one model is better than another?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And generally, where can you see, regression, right, is, maybe in your demand forecasting, financial analysis, so if you're trying to do some sort of
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Predictions, stock predictions,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You see, honestly, about stock predictions, there's a lot more research being done for more complex models, but a very… for a first-cut naive model, you can look at regression as a naive model first.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Scientific research as well,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: to predict all sorts of… I mean, if, let's say, you're looking at the healthcare, you want to predict, blood pressure, for example, or health rate, or if you want to predict,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, there are lots of different applications here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And for regression, something that we didn't touch is, but good to know is that you can also do polynomial regression. So today we learned linear regression, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Y equals beta 0 plus beta 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: plus beta 2X, right? You can also do polynomial, where maybe you have, like, Squares…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: or you have a lot. Basically, you have more… your regression is not linear, it's more polynomial in nature. So there's also something, it's an extension of linear regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And later on, you will also see that regression, you can use it for regularization. So, this is how you can, prevent overfitting of
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your models. So, you will see how regression can give you other types of regression, models, how you can use other types of regression models, for more regularization techniques.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hmm.
Kar Poh Tay: Compared to my question on the number of independent developers, and I understand about… you mentioned overfitting and underfitting. So the more independent developers equal, means that we are doing overfitting. But we'll only be known after we deploy the model, is it?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh, look, I shared.
Kar Poh Tay: Yep.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: No. When you… so, of course, when you deploy the model, you need to monitor it, but before you deploy the model, I was actually just going to come to it. For any data, right, we need to split this data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Into a test and a validation set.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you can test… so you will test on your testing set and your validation set. You will use your train set to train, and then you will test it
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that you can get an indication of how this potentially would… how this model will fare in the real world. Your… this is like your exam that you're taking, and then you can see what is the score that it got here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you will always test your model, first before you do any sort of deployment.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So.
Kar Poh Tay: Which means, based on these tests, we'll adjust the number of independent… I mean, thinking that they are all relevant, but…
Kar Poh Tay: We'll just have to adjust the number of independent variables based on the test results.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, so actually, okay, maybe I'll talk about that now first. We have… so we always have our data set, right? For any data set, right, typically, right, we would split it into a train test validation. Test data set here, right, we always keep this aside. This is, like, our final exam.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So we'll keep this away from the rest. We will never touch this until the last part.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, when we are doing validation, right, here we can try out different sort of parameters. We test, then we validate. We train here, we train on this training set, then we validate using this validation set, then we can change something, and then we validate again. So, we always test with this first, then finally.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We look at the holdup, this final test set, because, you know, if you train and test just on one test set, right, you may overfit to this test set also.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you always want to have one test set that you keep aside.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: fall.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: like, your final exam. Then this… you… you kind of play around with this train and validation set first.
Kar Poh Tay: Oh, yeah, thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Do we have access to this link you just now shared?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, yeah, okay, I'll paste all these links in the… In the chat.
Easwaran Jayaraman: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, before that, do y'all need a break, or do you think we can press on?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Everyone okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can… Anyone need something?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, okay. Maybe then we'll take a quick, 5-minute break. We'll come back at 9.13. Then when we come back, we'll go into the code.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And in the meantime, I'll send all the things in the… chips.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay… Welcome back, everybody.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think I see some of y'all coming back.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, let's get started.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So now we'll go into the code component. So we have 3 notebooks here, that we'll be going through today.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, the first one here we'll be looking at…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Linear regression. So, there's some notes here. I'll let you all read through it by yourself. Essentially, it's what we talked about, earlier today.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Really what we want to do now is to train our linear regression model. So, we'll come over to the hands-on portion. Here we have scikit-learn, skelearn.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sklearn is a library, that has already kind of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: developed all the different, models, machine learning models,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: put it very nicely inside this SKlearn library, so that, you know, just now we talked about how to fit a linear regression model, you need to either do OLS or gradient descent. You don't have to code everything out from scratch. SKlearn already has that covered for you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you can actually just import the sklearn library, and then, from there, you can define what model you want to use. Today, we'll be looking at the linear regression model. Yeah, and as simple as that, you will have your model, ready, and then you just need to fit this model on your own data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so some other things that we are importing here. First is, a train-test split. Train-test split, this really is what we talked about just now here, train-test split, right? So we have our data set.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And we want to be able to split it into a train and a test.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Generally, you want to… I mean, depends on how much data you have. You can do 80… 80-20, 70-30, 75-25, depending. This is a value that you can change.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, train-test split here, lets you train, split your train test… your data into a training set and a testing set.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, we talked about,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: performance evaluation, right? So when you want to evaluate a linear regression model, your metrics we'll look at typically is your mean square error and your R-squared, your R-squared score. So these two, again, you don't have to…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: code it out in terms of how to actually calculate your mean squared error. I mean, it's basically just your YI… your, your Y minus your prediction squared, average, right? But you don't have to, code all that out. SKLN has already covered that for you, okay? Same as your R squared.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, so just import all these, and then here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We're going to just generate a synthetic dataset, to fit our linear regression model on. So here, we're just creating,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: we set a random seed, so this random seed is such that, if you run the code at home and I run it here, we should see the same, results. Because if not, because we're using a random generator, right? If you run it and we don't set a random seed, you will see different values, okay? So typically, we want to set a random seed.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then here, we're just creating synthetic X data, synthetic, errors, and, Y value is just going to be, X+. So we've already sort of defined,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: our… Our intercept and our beta. But we want to see how well our,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: our linear regression model can fit and solve for this, okay? In a real-world scenario, you will never have your
Shumin Lai  | NTU: true values of, beta naught and beta 1. This is just a synthetic data set that we're looking at here today, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then, we're just going to split our data. So, train test split here from SKLearn, it would help you split your data into,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your training and your testing. So you just need to define your test size. If your test size is 20%, this just means that 80% of your data will be in your training.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? You have to give it your X values and your Y values, basically your independent and your dependent variables, and then select a random state again. This random state is really just to ensure for reproducibility.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? So, when you call this train-test split,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Function. What happens is that you will get 4, outputs.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: your X train, your X test, your Y train, and your Y test. So this just means that, so this, this helps you. So for your train data, you can train your linear regression model later on your training X and your training Y, then you can test it on your X test and your Y test.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Bucky?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, reshape here is just to ensure that we can fit this for SKLearn compatibility. Don't worry too much about this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Great.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then when you see your train shape and your test shape, you see that you have 80 rows for your training dataset, and 20 rows for your test dataset, or X.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So now, this is where the magic happens.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You just need to call your linear regression model, and do a dot fit.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And just like that, you're… you've trained your first linear regression model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so you can see, SikitLynn really makes it very easy for you. You just need to put in your training data set here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? And once you have your training data set, you fit it on this linear regression model, and then now you can just do a dot prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So now what's happening is, you know, for your train… your data set, right, you split it into your training and your testing, you are now using this testing dataset to check how good is this, model, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, you will then see that, when we run this model on your X test, you can calculate the mean square error. So for mean squared error, we will compare our tests and our prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? So, here we have our predictions. We predict from X tense.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Now, we want to compare our Y test and our Y predict.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Why test? We already created it previously here, from our test data set. This is the exact expected output. So now, we are just predicting, comparing our training, our test set, and our prediction.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, everyone clear so far?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: To calculate our mean square error, and then we also calculate our R-squared.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, very nicely here, you will then see that, fitting this in, our mean squared value is actually 0.194, and our R-squared value is 0.68. So, this linear regression model that we fit can explain about 68… about 70% of the variation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In Y, the X can explain about 70% of the variation in Y, and for the mean square error, it's about 0.194.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this just means that for every prediction we made.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the error… the mean squared error is about 0.194. It was about 0.194 units mean squared off from the actual
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, you can also use the model to find your coefficient and your intercept.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And you'll see that the coefficient is 0.26, and the intercept is 0.2.0. So you can compare this with your
Shumin Lai  | NTU: actual, right, because this was the actual… the true date… true value was 2 and 0.3. With this linear regression model, we got 2 and 0.26, 2.0 and 0.26, so the slope is a little bit off, but, yeah, because of the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Errors. And we can only explain about 70% of the variation.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, if you were to plot, you can, you can actually plot this,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: linear regression model. So you can see all these blue points here, these are your data set, this is your, your, your real data, and then this,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Line is the best fit line, your linear regression line that you have trained.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so you can see, to train a linear regression model is really not that difficult. You can just fit in, just need to have your data fitted in and trained.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? Of course, here today we are looking at a synthetic dataset. In the real world, when you bring in a dataset,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think in Module 2, you have already learned about your different data, cleaning, data preprocessing steps that you will need to do before you finally fit a model. So you need to… here, we're assuming that it's an ideal data science world, where you have your data engineer who has already done all the data cleaning,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: transformation and all that ready for you. You just take in all that data and do your training.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of course, real world may not be so simple. You may actually need to… I mean, you of course need to study your data, understand your data, look for anomalies within your data. All that data preprocessing steps will need to come in first before you finally fit your model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, here we are using sklearn to fit the model. You can go back and look at the rest. There's also another, library that you can use, which is stats model. So this one is slightly more…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: statistical, in nature, you will see that, there's a few more statistical tests that is done to ensure, the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Ensure that your model is statistically significant.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So I'll leave y'all to go through that in your free time.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that is for regression. I'll now go through, another model, which is logistic regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we just went through linear regression, right? Linear regression is a regression-based model, which allows us to do predictions of continuous values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Logistic regression, on the other hand, is a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, we are looking at more of a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, the aim is really to predict, discrete classes based on data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, logistic regression, the name is a bit of a misnomer, it's not exactly… because the name here kind of suggests that it's a regression nature, right? But, it's actually a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this name was… yeah, it's a bit of a misnomer. But a bit of context, logistic regression is actually a type of generalized linear model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And why, right? So, if you actually look at this, equation here, this is a sigmoid function.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Something like that. And you'll notice, hidden inside this sigmoid function is actually our linear regression model, right? If you look over here closely.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can see that this is our linear regression model that we're trying to fit.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So logistic regression is actually a type of general model. So that's where the regression really comes from. But ultimately, it's really more of a… at the end of the day, it is a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That's just a bit of his background on the name, so don't worry too much about it. But logistic regression, really, a key thing to note is a classification model, and typically, we will use it more for binary classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, I'll take this point to quickly explain the difference. We have something called binary classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A multi-class.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And multi-label.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Anyone know the difference between the three?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What are these three different types of classification?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Binary, quick guess, binary, as the name suggests.
Phillip Tan: Binary means two… two options, I guess.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, exactly. Thanks, Philip. So, by the way, yeah, as the name suggests, just two options. So, you're looking at spam or not spam.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or you could be looking at, Cat or dog.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, it means your classification only has two classes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If you are looking at a classification that has more classes, for example, you want to
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, let me go.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or hamster, for example, right? Multiple classes. This is when you look at a multi-class classification, so you can have multiple classes. And of course, it's not limited to four, you can have,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What else? Maybe.
Phillip Tan: cookbooks.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Types of butts, yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You have different types of birds?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Per, like, owls, whether it's an owl, you're looking at sparrow, Sorry, Green Falcon.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Etc. Another famous dataset you will see later is a handwriting dataset, so whether it's a 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, whether you're writing a number, whether it's 1, 2, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, what number is it? Handwriting? Yeah, so you can see that multi-class, you can have multiple classes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Finally, multi-label. Multilabel just means…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you can have multiple labels. So, within a photograph, right, it's not always, it's just a cat or a dog, right? You could also have cat and dog.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Or you can just have a cat. Or you can have a cat, and a dog, and a hamster.
Phillip Tan: Me.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Multilabel allows you to have multiple, as the name suggests, multiple… multiple classes, and…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, multiple… not just multi… multi-class, but multiple classes in one output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so these are the different types of classification. So, multi-label classification, you may see this more on your social media, right? When you have images, you want to have multiple labels. When you're also, again, maybe when you're looking at products, right? You're looking at clothes, maybe you can have shirt.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: dresses, pants, but you can have, floral with shirt. I mean, so basically, you can have multiple classes, attached to that output.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Sorry.
Phillip Tan: The self-driving cars, when they draw a box on, like, people, car, bicycle, that's also multi-labour, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That is object detection, yeah, I would think it's a multi-label object detection, yes, yes, yes, because you can have multiple, yeah, you can have multiple labels, exactly, yeah, so yeah, good point.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Thanks, Billy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so yeah, so there are many different types of classification that we have, but for today, when we are looking at logistic regression, we will be focusing on binary classification, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We'll be focusing on this today. But later in the other modules, you will also get to see other versions of this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so just bear this in mind. But for today, we will focus on binary classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for logistic regression,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: this is the… This is what we are trying to… this is the equation that we're trying to come up with. So, you know, just now for linear regression, right, we had beta naught plus beta 1…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: X1 plus error, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Y equals to this. For logistic regression, this is what we're trying to predict.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This is what we're trying to come up with at the end of the day.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This sigmoid function.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, why a sigmoid function, right? If you look at a linear regression, you know, just now when we were predicting salary prices, right, or housing prices.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Once you have the best fit line, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This line can go on almost, like, technically forever, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: and down.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Right? But for logistic regression classification, when we are training this, we want to squish our output to be strictly between 0 and 1 as a probability.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So we don't want a scenario where the number is outside 0 and 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because we want to predict, ultimately for logistic regression, we're predicting a probability that, this is… this output is in class cat or class dog.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: plus spam, or class, not spam, for example. Okay? So, this is where the sigmoid function actually does that. It helps us to squish this, line very nicely between 0 and 1.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so you will never have a value above 1, nor will you ever have a value below 0.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for linear regression, I'll just quickly go through this concept. We, need to be, we need to know… be aware of this concept called opts and lockouts.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For this, I will just quickly go through, this link. I've also sent this to the chat previously, so later on you can also go and look through this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So you can see for logistic regression, ultimately we want to predict classes, right, whether it's rainy or sunny, for example. So you can see here, in this data set, we have sunny and rainy, and we want to fit it, we want to fit this sigmoid function.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, we want to find what is this best… what's the best curve that we can have, such that, we can correctly predict when the day is supposed to be sunny, or when the day is supposed to be rainy, just based off the temperature.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so once we have this curve, right, we can then see, based on, let's say, the temperature at 60, we can see that, oh, the probability is 0.08, for example, so this should be rainy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If, let's say, the temperature is maybe 75, then you'll see that, oh, okay, the probability that it is sunny is 1, very high.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so we want to, through logistic regression, fit this, sigmoid curve on our data, such that we adjust this curve such that, it will be able to predict for new data coming in as much as possible, whether the class should be sunny or rainy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, because here we're looking at a binary classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? So, you can set a threshold.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Because here, generally, right, for logistic regression, you can just set a threshold at 0.5. So for anything that is, greater than 0.5,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: it's gonna be sunny. Anything… the probability is less than 0.5, it's gonna be rainy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so for example, here, if we set a classification threshold to just be 0.5, if the temperature is 66 degrees Fahrenheit, you'll see that we predict this to be a sunny day.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If the temperature is… 62 degrees Fahrenheit, you see that the probability is about
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Mmm, 0.32, and so this is going to be a rainy day.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, but of course, this threshold, you can adjust it. Maybe, you want to accurately capture all the
Shumin Lai  | NTU: you want… when you say it's a sunny day, you want to be very sure that it's a sunny day. So you can have your threshold higher. If you want, you can have your threshold at 0.9, for example. So, in this kind of situation, you see that when your temperature is 65,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's actually predicted as a rainy day.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this threshold is something that you can play around with.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, ultimately, this is the curve that you want to fit, and you also want to figure out a good threshold.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this threshold, for now, I'll call it something a bit like a hyperparameter that you can tune.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And in the later modules, you'll… this will make more sense to you when you look at hyperparameter tuning, as to what is the best value you can choose.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so now don't worry too much about it, you can just take it as, you want to choose a value of 0.5, or 0.8, or 0.7, etc.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for a logistic regression model, similar to our linear regression model, we have a loss function that we want to minimize,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In this case, we will be minimizing our lock loss.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: don't worry too much about this. Essentially, this is the value that we want to, it's how we want to fit our beta naught and beta 1 values again. So, similar to linear regression to fit beta naught, beta 1, we can use OL as our gradient descent. Similarly, for logistic regression, to fit the beta naught and beta 1 values that you saw
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Here, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: inside our sigmoid, function, you see the beta naught and beta 1. We also want to figure out what's the values for this. So to do that, we can essentially just,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: fit the coefficients, and again, two approaches. One way you can use gradient descent. So you iteratively change this curve, and then see what the error is like, and then you find out what is the best beta naught and beta 1 value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Another way is to maximize the likelihood estimation, or basically minimize the log loss. So.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Similar to linear regression, two different ways you can go about doing this to estimate your beta naught and beta 1 values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Again,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Don't worry, because when you come to the code, you will see that later, we will just call logistic regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You see here, we will just call out this digression, and the maximizing of, the maximizing likelihood estimation, or gradient is done behind the scenes for you, and you will get your beta naught and beta 1 values very nicely, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, but if you are interested, yeah, I would, you can go through this, page as well to find out more about Gradient Descent or the MLE here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But for today, let's focus more on how to actually use this logistic regression, how to interpret it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, similar to your linear regression, right, where we talk about the coefficients, your coefficient, like, for example, salary has a… when there's a one-unit increase, right, call over here…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: A one-unit increase in experience leads to a 20… a 2,000 increase in salary.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Same thing for logistic regression. We can also interpret, the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the beta naught and beta 1, but the interpretation will be slightly different, okay? So first, we need to understand the concept of odds.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Odds is a bit like probability. So, if I were to say that the odds of Sunu.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Rainy?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Liz. 3, 2, 1?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This just means that for 5 days.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 1, 2, 3… sorry, for 4 days, 3 days will be Sunday.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, the probability of a sunny day is 0.75.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In one day, Out of 4?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: We'll be green.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this will be 0.25.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is odds.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so if I say the odds of, the odds of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: winning a competition is 3 is to 2, right? If I say 3 is to 2, this just means the odds of winning is 3 by 5, which is about 60%.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And the odds of losing is 2.5, which is 40%.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, this is odds.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Everyone, okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's just a… So, once we have odds.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Now we can look at something called log odds, because, actually, our coefficients are in a log odds scale.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this means that if, let's say, our coefficient is negative 0.7, Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This means that the log odds
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, sorry. Let's say here we are looking at sunny, probability that it's sunny if it is foggy, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, if it is foggy, then our log odds ratio decreases by 0.7.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Log odds ratio decreases by 0.7, so if we convert it to odds, we just need to exponential this value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Which is 0.5. So this means the odds Will…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Multiply by half, which is, essentially, your odds will, is less… is half less, compared to if it's not.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? So, to interpret, your beta naught and your beta 1 coefficients, instead of looking at it from an absolute value perspective, we are now looking at it from a log odds perspective, and to make it more interpretable, you can exponential the value so that it becomes an odds.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And odds is basically this.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, because logistic regression, ultimately, at the end of the day, we're looking at more probability. What's the probability of it being sunny? Probability of it being rainy, right? So, that's why even for the interpretation of these coefficients, we're looking at it more from an odds and a log odds perspective.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any questions?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It may be a bit confusing, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I advise you to go home, I mean, in your time, in your free time, go back and digest this, and then this will make more sense, okay? And then if you have any questions, feel free to just put it in the Discord, and I'll see if I can answer them.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, it's… essentially, it's just interpreting how you can interpret, the coefficients for large-state regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: P.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that is for your odds and log odds to interpret your, coefficients for large-state regression. But to…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: train a logistic regression model is really, a lot simpler. So what we're going to do, right, first we're going to load in the data, and in this dataset, we're actually using this dataset called the IRIS dataset. So, I'll just quickly introduce this IRIS dataset.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Iris dataset is a very popular introduction to machine learning dataset.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That you'll see a lot of tutorials use, for classification tasks.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So if you go online and you search, introduction to Classification, right, more often than not, you will see, either the Titanic dataset or this Iris dataset.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, to give a bit of context, a bit of color in this Irish dataset, right, what happens is we have these three, flowers, Iris satosa, Versicola, and, Virginica, and these three
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Flowers have different petal and sepal, widths… width.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: lengths, rather. So, we want to try to build a model
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That takes in these petal and sepo lengths, and then try to predict which of the flowers it is.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay? As simple as that. We're just trying to predict what flower this is based on the petal and sepole length.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The sample length, sample width, petal length, petal width. So these are the different,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Features that we have.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And from there, we want to predict, is it Irisida, versicolor, or Virginica?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that is the dataset that we have. So we're just going to load in this dataset, and it comes from the sklearn dataset as well. You can load it in. And then here, we're just going to convert it to a binary classification. So we're just going to take classes 1 and 3.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: yeah, for the purpose of binary classification, we're just gonna do a binary classification today. But you… if you go back and try removing this, right, you can actually just… you can run a multi-class classification on logistic regression as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, but for now, we're just going to do a binary classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Again, you're going to do a train-test split, test size is about 30%, give your X and Y, and then, very simply, just call your logistic regression model, and then do a .fit, and then…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Fit it on your training data, and now you can predict.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So… once done, you can actually, yeah, so this logic regression actually,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: abstracts away how you predict the… how you come up with the beta naught and beta-1 values, but, it's already done for you. And then you can actually just, do an accuracy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, for regression, if you recall, we use mean squared error to evaluate how good a model is.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For classification tasks, there are other metrics. Accuracy is one of them. I think in the next lesson, you will see what are some other metrics you can use, why accuracy may not always be the best metric.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But for today, let's just use accuracy, and you'll see that this actually… this classification model actually has an accuracy of 100%.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So it was able to correctly,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Classify all the different color, the different flower types based on the sepole length width and petal length width.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then now, you can just do a, a plot, and then you can see that, actually visually, it's pretty obvious that, there is some separation between these two colors, these two.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: flowers.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And this was what your logistic regression model predicted. So it was correctly able to predict all, the purple color ones together, and the yellow color, ones together.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you see that it's very easy to, train a logistic regression model as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The key thing really is to know, based on different types of models, what are the different metrics you want to use to evaluate.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So if you see, for linear regression, the metric that we used was mean square error.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And of course, you can use R-square.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For a classification model, today we are just using the accuracy.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So if, let's say, tomorrow you have a new dataset and you train another model, you can then compare, is the accuracy also 100%?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: How does the accuracy differ across different models, so that you'll be able to choose, the best model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, I will power through the last, notebook.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this… is yet another machine learning model that we have. It's called K-Nearest Neighbors. K-nearest Neighbors
Shumin Lai  | NTU: It's actually a very, to put it rather crudely, a lazy model, in the sense that you are not actually training anything.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: K-Nearest Mall… K-Nearest Neighbours, right, as the name suggests. You are looking at…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The neighbors to decide what is the… Class, or what is the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: prediction. So, keynearest neighbors can be used for both regression and classification.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so how can nearest neighbors work? I'll just quickly show you through this visualization.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: What happens, right, is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: K is a value, a hyperparameter, again, that you can choose. Let's say we choose K equals to 8.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: if I have this new dataset coming in, it basically finds who are my 8 closest data points, and then classifies it based on that 8 closest data points.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, if I have another data point here, I'll then take the 8 closest again, and let's say all these 8 are red, I'll then say, okay, this guy should have… should be in the red class.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so you can see that,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: K-nearest neighbors, really, what happened… what's happening is, for every single data point, it's identifying who are my nearest other data points. You can think of it really as, buds of the same feather flocked together, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: for every single data point coming in, what… who are the… what is the behavior of the nearest data points like? And then we'll just take the average or the majority of them.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Vicki?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And so, how do we decide nearest neighbors, right? We are actually using something called a distance metric.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I'm not sure if you have heard of Euclidean distance already. Euclidean distance is just one of many different types of distance metrics that you can use.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Euclidean distance, essentially what's happening is we're taking
Shumin Lai  | NTU: let's say if it's square feet… let's say if we are trying to, predict square feet of… predict, housing price, right? What happens is you can just take, square feet of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the… data point.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Minus the square feet of…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You will take, square feet of, data, Minus square feet off.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Oh, mute that.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Minus square feet off.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Training data.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Square?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then square root.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So this is your Euclidean distance.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then you do that for every single data point, and then you find out which one has the closest distance.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so, maybe… The notebook will be a bit more apparent.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is your, Euclidean distance. So, essentially, you take, your… your…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: training data, I mean, your new data point coming in, minus your, your data points within your data set, and then you square it, and square root.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So that would be the distance. And this is Euclidean distance that we're looking at. Of course, there are other distances, like Manhattan distance, Minkowski distance, that, again, this is considered a hyperparameter that you can…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Change, and then see which distance gives you the best, lowest error rate, or best accuracy, depending if you're doing a regression or a classification model.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, so, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: K-nearest neighbors, really, it's just identifying who are your nearest neighbors, and then, from there, getting the majority, or the average, or median of, that value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, really, for k nearest neighbors, right, you are not exactly training any model. Your training data is really just going to be a model, in the sense that for every new data point coming in, right, you will calculate the distance from that data point to all your other data points, choose the top K, and then…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Go from there.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Everyone okay with your nearest neighbor?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Any questions?
Chieh Cheng Lai: Sorry, can you repeat the last sentence? You mean they are not the training?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So for k-nearest neighbors, right, what happens, right, is that,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For a new data point coming in, right, I actually calculate the distance to every single data point.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And then, right, I find out that these…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Are the nearest 8 data points.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: But actually, I would have calculated all the distances, so that means I would have calculated this, this, this, this, this, but then I only choose the top 8.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, then from there, from this top 8, right, I see that 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 6 are blue.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And 2 are red. So majority is blue, so that's why this new data point is blue.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, so then I can have another data point, let's say here. Again, for this data point, right, I would already have calculated all the distances with all the data points. But then, I found out that for this data point,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: These are the top 8.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This tree, and these four.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So then I see majority are blue, so this is classified as blue.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Yeah, I understand.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, so I can choose any value for the K value.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, correct. You can try different venues. So, you can have…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Here, we can see until 15, but of course, I mean, up to you to change this K value, however you want.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, this is considered a hyperparameter, that we can tune.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And in later classes, you will see that… how you can deal with hyperparameter through different things like, grid searching, so you can try different K values and see which one gives you the best performance.
Chieh Cheng Lai: So, will this care value be affected by the outliers?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, that's a very good question. So, yes. So, depending… so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If you have a K, for example, okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Try something else.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So see if I have…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, see these points, right? Initially, it's red, blue, red, right? Depending on the K I choose, right? You can see the colors change.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Based on the… yeah. So, you would then try for K equals to 4, K equals to 5, K equals to 6, and see which one gives you the best
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If, let's say, you're looking at accuracy, classification, see which one gives you the best accuracy. If you are looking at regression, you will then calculate all the mean squared errors for k equals to 4, k equals to 5, what's the mean square error, k equals to 6, what's the mean squared error, k equals to 7, what's the mean square error? Then from there, you can choose what is the best K value.
Chieh Cheng Lai: Okay, understood. Thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, that is k-nearest neighbors, essentially.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, Knearest Neighbours,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I will just quickly go through this. Here today we're looking at a regression problem, and we are trying to predict
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the number of carats in a diamond. I'm not wrong. So, this is the diamonds dataset that we have. So you can see, we have carrots, color, clarity, depth, etc, all these different, information that we have about a diamond.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, and then, we're going to do the same thing, train time split, test set of 30%, and then, train this k-nearest neighbors model, k-nearest regressor, okay? And then you see that,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: sorry, we're predicting the diamond's price based on the number of carats. So then you see here,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Number of neighbors is gonna be 5, but you can try different values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, let's say, I try k equals to 5, right? Then you see that my mean squared error
Shumin Lai  | NTU: 4K equals to 5 is…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: About 2.3 million.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: is mining square error.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, you can actually try different K values.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So here, right, we're trying K equals to…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: From k equals to 1 all the way to K equals to 20.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For K in range 1 to 21, so it's from 1 to 20, and then you are seeing what is your mean squared error.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And… Just nice, in this scenario, you see that your mean square error is decreasing.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This is testing on your test set.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: it's decreasing up to a certain point where it plateaus. So maybe here you want to choose, like, k equals to 15, for example, where your value is, lower.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: yeah, here you are just plotting your error against your K value. So here you can see for different, different kind of K values, what is your mean squared error like?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so generally, yeah, K, right, is a pretty sensitive number. You don't want to choose too big, but you also don't want to choose too small, so,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: yeah, usually you would, try different K values, and then empirically, you'd be able to see what's the performance, like, across different K values, and make your decision from there.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So in this scenario, very nicely, you see your error is dropping, right? Depending on your data set, you can also sometimes… you may see a scenario where it's like that, then suddenly it can spike up, for example.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then you know that, okay, I should choose K because I bought 5.5.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: This one…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Very nicely, your mean squared error just keeps decreasing, so you may want to choose a larger… slightly larger K value here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, I think quite a lot of content covered today, so I advise all of you to go back and spend some time to digest this,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think… Yes, spend some time, first understanding what are these different,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think key thing today, really, is to understand what are the different types of machine learning models, right? We learn about regression and classification, and then understand the different ways to evaluate it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Then, if you have a bit more bandwidth, if you can go back and understand how to interpret the different coefficients, that would be very useful as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, are there any questions?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hey, if there are no questions, I'll just pull up the Slido.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Excuse me.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: If y'all can just spend some time, going through the… Coming here.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In the meantime, if there are any questions, feel free to ask as well.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hmm, so, what did we learn today?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, yeah, today definitely was, very content-heavy. You were introduced to many different types of models, and,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Definitely a lot.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: mastery.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So I'll advise all of you to go back and, maybe just…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Go through the slides and the code again, just to make sure that, you understood all of it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So what you learned today, I see a lot of regression.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: SKLAN classification, so yeah, mainly we learn about different machine learning models,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: different types of machine learning models, classification, regression, these are all part of supervised learning, right? And under supervised learning, you can do regression-based models, or…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: classification-based models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And sklearn is one of the Python libraries that you can use, to model these classification and regression models.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I see R-squared tests, so yeah, for each of these regression, each of these models, it's always good to know how to evaluate it, because you want to be able to compare, across different models, which one should I actually deploy, which one should I push to production,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Of course, Using the metrics would be one good way to help you evaluate.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: B.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, I will move on to the next question.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Which topics did you find most difficult or challenging today?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The formulas, okay, all the different math, yeah. Yeah, definitely a lot of math for,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: machine learning, and you will start to see a lot more math, coming in as well. I would say
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For the math part of it,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I think it's good for us to understand what each of these models do. So you don't necessarily know the math behind, but know that, okay, for linear regression, it is a regression-based model, and understand that it is more of a linear model, and what are the assumptions?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: For classification, we have logistic aggression, right? So to know what is a logistic aggression model,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: and how it works, so it helps you classify, for example, binary classification, right, and how to evaluate it. The math part, of course, if you can go back and understand that, that would be great. But I would say right now, at this point of time, it's not,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: the most necessary yet. So, first to understand the different types of models, and how to evaluate it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hmm.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I'll move on to the next question.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: How's the peace of today's class?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, that's good.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Most of you say it's just nice, a little bit fast.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, we did cover quite a lot of models today, so…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: I'm… yeah. If you say it's fast, I'm not… yeah,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Spend some time to go back and digest it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: G.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So yeah, I think definitely, spend some time self-studying after this, so that,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can better digest a lot of the content covered today.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, move on to the next question. What went well for you in today's class?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: No, those… oh, good.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Learning ML, understanding ML. Okay.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: That's good. So I think, ultimately, today was an introduction to ML, so… understanding…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Understanding, the different types of models and what to expect, will be important for your next few classes.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: letting him know.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Move on to the last question. So, what will you improve on after today's session?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Revice and digest.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, yeah, I love it.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Revising and reading up.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, I'm playing with the interactive website, it's nice. Yeah, so yeah, so all the links are in the chat, and…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: You can also find all the links in the… in the slide.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, even for this, if you want to go back and try, then you can also play around with the different, business metrics. But, all these things will be here in the slides, so you can, go back and try and play around with all the…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: In your free time.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, okay, I think, yeah, lots of, revision and reading up. So I think, Jermaine also mentioned in the chat that he'll be collecting all the questions for the coaching session this Saturday. So, if there's any further clarifications that you would like, please feel free to put it on Discord.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And if there's any questions not answered, I'll also try to… I mean, if you have any burning questions, for a Discord, I'll also try to answer.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, so if there are no other questions, I shan't hold you back anymore, it's really 10 or 6. Thanks everyone for staying back,
Shumin Lai  | NTU: And, yeah. Good night, and take care.
Lily Seah: Thank you.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Ew.
Lik Hong Eng: Beautiful.
Phillip Tan: Sorry, can I ask for the, K nearest neighbor?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah.
Phillip Tan: The new point is not, it's not used in the measurements, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: The new points… what do you mean by that?
Phillip Tan: the Euclidean… let's say the Euclidean distance is actually calculated against the existing points, not the new points that come in, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, correct, correct. So your training data set ultimately, is your universe.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: then if, let's say, you want to bring in new points, right, then you need to re-value it again. So, let's say, you know, like, next month, right, you actually collect more data, right?
Phillip Tan: Sorry, going back to the part where you were actually adding points, and then auto-calculated the 8 nearest neighbor, the nearest neighbor is always against the underlying data, not the new points that are added, right?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yes, correct, correct, correct, correct, exactly. I mean, if you want to include new points, I wouldn't really recommend it, because it's not…
Phillip Tan: It was cute.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, correct, and it's not trained yet. These new points are not, verified yet, so you should only add it once it's verified, then you'll be included. Yeah, but yeah, good question.
Phillip Tan: Thanks.
Phillip Tan: Okay, bye-bye.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Bye-bye, good night. Thank you.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Hi, hi, Jimmy. Can I share my screen? The notebook… the notebook one, I can,
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): I can run. My notebook 2 and Notebook 3, I don't know why I cannot run.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Nutrition…
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Goodbye.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): He doesn't… he doesn't…
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, okay, yeah, Daniel, go ahead.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): I should ask you going on.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Okay, part one, I can write now. Like, for example…
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Okay, Ryan.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Lose it. Okay.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): What part two… What do I carry around tonight?
Shumin Lai  | NTU: So, I see you right?
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Yo, I have this… hang.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Maybe if you re… hang on. Maybe if you close and open again.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Were you writing a lot of things previously?
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Oh, okay, so it just crossed the opener.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Yeah, sometimes maybe if you ran a lot of things, there's a cache, then it was loading, or something was still running in the background.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Usually, yeah.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Oh, boy.
Daniel Chan Chee Seng (Chen Zhisheng): Okay, thank you so much.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Okay, no problem.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Hey, if there are no other questions, I will be ending this section.
Shumin Lai  | NTU: Thanks, everyone.